A Guide to the Alice Barber Stephens Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #8789
Alice Barber Stephens Collection 1892-1907
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
8789
11 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase [ 1967 October 4 ] 1968 January 25
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - Essay about her painting, "A Girl in a Garden", n. d.; AMsS, 3 p.
    [Explains a painting she did of her mother and in which she tried to show the essence of young womanhood in the middle of the 19th century.]
- Letters and Documents
  - Receipt from Alice Barber Stephens to Ladies' Home Journal, 1892 October 29; ADS, 1 p.
    [Acknowledges receipt of $75.00 for the drawing: "The New Year Minuet."]
  - Alice Barber Stephens to Edward W. Bok, 1893 November 14; ALS, 2 p.
    [Informs Bok of her willingness to work for
    Ladies' Home Journal
    if they allow her enough time.]
  - Receipt from Alice Barber Stephens to Ladies' Home Journal, 1893 December 20; ADS, 1 p.
    [Acknowledges receipt of $50.00 for illustration for story, "
    Miss Maria's Fiftieth
    . "]
  - Alice Barber Stephens to Edward W. Bok, 1894 January 21; ALS, 4 p.
    [Replies in regard to the return of two pictures loaned by Bok for the World's Exposition. Explains that they are to be next in an exhibit to assist a young ladies' Studio Society in showing the wealthy and powerful of Philadelphia the increasing vitality of the city's painters, sculptors, architects, etc. Offers him a new photograph of herself for the Journal. Mentions a Mr. Guild and an Academy exhibition.]
  - Alice Barber Stephens to Edward W. Bok, 1894 March 8; ALS, 1 p.
    [Comments on her new photograph: it is not satisfactory to her, but she will let him judge. Responds to his inquiry re a biographical article for the Journal. Mentions Mr. Guild.]
  - Receipt from Alice Barber Stephens to Ladies' Home Journal, 1894 November 24; ADS, 1 p.
    [Acknowledges receipt of $35.00 for cover design for "
    A Girl of the Directory
  - Alice Barber Stephens to William Valentine Alexander, 1907 February 6; ALS, 2 p.
    [Acknowledges receipt of pages of photographic reproduction. Mentions Miss McLaughlin.]
  - Alice Barber Stephens to unknown, n. d.; ANS, 1 p.
    [Thanks unidentified person for a "Valentine."]
  - Alice Barber Stephens to unknown, n. d.; ALS (last page), 1 p.
    [Fragment beginning... "with an author's thought... "]
- Photograph
  - Alice Barber Stephens, head and shoulders, from a magazine, Photo